<?xml version="1.0"?>
<document>
  <content>Shristika Adhikari
Email Id:  shristikaadhikari88@gmail.comMobile:    +91 8658021291
Linkedln:  Shristika AdhikariGitHub:  Shristika Adhikari
Education
•
Biju Patnaik University Of TechnologyOdisha, India
Bachelor of Technology - Electronics and Telecommunication; CGPA till 6th Semester: 8.4  Nov 2021 - May 2025
Skills Summary
•Languages:Python, C, C++, JavaScript,HTML,CSS SQL, JAVA
•Frameworks:React.js, TensorFlow, Keras, Scikit-learn , Laravel, Node.js,Next.js, TypeScript, TensorFlow, Django, Flask
•Tools:GIT, Git-hub, MySQL, SQLite, Figma, WordPress, Web-Socket
•Technical:Linear Regression, Logistic Regression,Support Vector Machines, Naive Bayes, K-Means, Hierarchical
Clustering, CNNs, RNNs, LSTM, Matplotlib, Seaborn, Pandas, NumPy, LLM
Experience
•
Rework AIRemote
Software Engineer Intern (Remote)February 2024 - October 2024
◦Development:  Enhanced and created responsive web pages using HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Tailwind CSS and react.
Engineered a real-time video calling platform using Web-Sockets, ensuring seamless communication.
◦Libraries:  Implemented Kafka for efficient event-driven communication and Node.js for back-end scalability, and
developed a collaborative coding platform with Kafka, docker and Node.Js, fostering teamwork.
◦Integration and collaboration:  Successfully implemented and maintained API integrations, ensuring seamless
communication between diverse systems and enhancing overall platform functionality and Proficiently utilized Git,
GitHub and Vercel for code collaboration
•
PMN Patralok(Punama Innovation)Remote
Software Developer Lead Intern (Remote)October 2023 - March 2024
◦Web development:  Led and managed a team of 6 to 7 interns, achieving a significant percentage improvement in
project efficiency and output through effective leadership and management.
◦Libraries:  Employed jQuery, PHP and Bootstrap libraries to expedite front-end and backend development, leading to a
40% reduction in time spent on UI implementation and a boost in overall team efficiency.
◦Frameworks:  Pioneered the integration of React and Laravel frameworks, empowering the creation of dynamic user
interfaces, resulting in a 25% increase in user engagement and a 15% boost in conversion rates.
◦Version control and Troubleshooting:  Proficiently utilized Git and GitHub for code collaboration and resolved PMN
page front-end issues, ensuring seamless website performance.
•
Teach for India NGORemote
English Tutor (Volunteer)October 2023 - Present
Fostered communication and collaboration by actively engaging with fellow volunteers, teachers, and NGO staff
to orchestrate activities and exchange best practices.
•
Grey nodesRemote
Technical content writer(Freelance)April 2023 - June 2023
◦Technical content:  Adhered to company policies and editorial guidelines while producing comprehensive and
well-crafted technical content.Produced documentation that elucidate the product’s features and benefits.
Projects
•Criminal Face Recognition System using Yolov8 and FaceNet (Python, Deep Learning, Yolo ):  Designed an
integrated face recognition system using Yolo v8 and FaceNet providing an accuracy of 97.6% to identify criminals in real time
effectively.  (Dec’25)
•Spoof Detection (Tensorflow.js, Python , Flask, MobileNet, CNN , Deep learning):   The objective of this project
was to develop an interface for face anti-spoofing model using deep learning techniques to distinguish between real and spoofed
faces.  Initially, the code organizes the dataset by creating new directories for training and testing, and then splits the dataset
into these directories.  Dataset and Libraries:  XML, Kaggle, Roboflow(July ’24)
•CodeGreez(React js, JavaScript, Node.js ,Machine Learning, Python ):  This is a real time time code editor which is
proctored by AI . This aims to provide the interviewer to test the candidate in real-time proctored environment.  (May’24)
Volunteer Experience
•
Coordinator of TCS nqtOdisha, India
Orchestrated and facilitated the successful execution of the TCS NQT examination on the campus.July 2023
•
Volunteer in NSSJuly 2023</content>
</document>